# Christopher Ducharme

## **Professional Summary**

Business professional with direct sales experience in the consumer products industry. Experience leading a store-front location towards successful qualitative and quantities sales goals year over year. Passion for developing collaborative personal relationships while driving towards business development, innovation, and growth.

#### **Skills**

- Account Management
- Brand Development
- Business Strategy
- Contract Negotiation

- Human Resource Management
- Product Marketing Innovation
- Talent Development
- Conflict Resolution

## **Work Experience**

Branch Manager

December 2018-January 2020

Ladd's Turf, Golf & Utility, Jackson, MS

Decreased expenses by streamlining training and reducing unbilled overtime. Managed all HR Functions including counseling and corrective action, benefits and payroll. Ensure Daily Branch Operations follow regulator guidelines and successfully passed annual internal audits.

- Managed Branch staff of five along with coordinating daily with 12 department heads spread over 5 branches.
- Streamlined Fleet Truck scheduled and increased Pickup and Delivery Revenue by 7%
- Oversaw complete store front remodel, which included re-arrangement of aisles to direct customer flow toward higher profit merchandise.

# Commercial Sales Representative

June 2015-November 2018

Ladd's Turf, Golf & Utility, Jackson, MS

Generated Sales leads through cold calling, telemarking, conference networking and referrals. Processed orders, quotes and proposals in accordance to Mississippi State Contract requirements. Anticipate Customer Account needs with positive solutions in a timely manner.

- Utilizing cold calling and onsite meetings, unit sales increased by 46%
- By employing EKA Government Contract Databases and partnering with U.S. Communities Government Purchasing Alliance, Mississippi State contract sales increased by 32%

#### Service Agent

Enterprise Rent-A-Car, Richmond, KY

August 2014- May 2015

- Created daily route to chauffer customers around the Metropolitan area.
- Provided customer service via phone regarding rental car reservations.
- Executed transactions of rental cars between Lexington Branch and Enterprise HUB at airport.

### Intern

Big Springs Country Club, Louisville, KY

May 2013-August 2013

- Served as initial contact with members in pro shop via telephone, email, in person.
- Executed set up for monthly tournaments for members and public.

- Collaborated with operations team and executed marketing strategies to engage members at club.
- Coached children ages 4-14 in junior clinic for 8 weeks.

#### Intern

Oldham County Country Club, Buckner, KY

May 2012-August 2012

- Educated children ages 4-14 in the OCCC Junior Golf Program for 10 weeks.
- Assisted staff in the pro shop with shipment, and accounting information.
- Organized clubhouse apparel and accessory displays.
- Assisted with Rules Marking to prepare golf course to be tournament ready.

#### Education

Bachelor of Business Administration

Graduated May 2015

Eastern Kentucky University, Richmond, KY

• Major: Business Management

# **Skills Training**

PGA Apprentice

Fall 2011-Present

Professional Golf Association

• Level 2 qualification